Amiri Baraka papers 6909686
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series III: Teaching, 1976-2006
  This series contains materials relating to Baraka's long career as a teacher at various colleges and universities, largely in the New York City area. Included are course descriptions, syllabi, rosters, correspondence with other faculty and administration, grades and graded tests and papers (currently restricted), and financial documents relative to his employment at each institution. The bulk of the items in this series are from Baraka's time at SUNY-Stony Brook, which contains materials pertaining to his anti-apartheid activism, and Rutgers, with much material about the controversy over his tenure denial. Also included in the series are writings and other materials surrounding the academic tenure of Professor Ernest Dube. This series is arranged alphabetically by institution. Material that includes student records or grades are closed for a period of 75 years from date of creation
  - Adelphi University, 1996 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - AFS420 Writer's Workshop, Undated (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Barnard College, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Brooklyn College, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Columbia University
    - General, 1978-1999 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - "The Politics of Art: Cultural Revolution and the Black Arts Movement(s)", 2001-2002 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Grades, 1977-2004 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Malcolm X Writers Workshop, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - Naropa, 1978-2006 (Box 50, Folder 9)
  - New York University, 1985-1986 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - New York University Artist-in-Residence, 1996-1998 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Rutgers, 1976-1993
    - General, 1989-1990 (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - "Art and the Political Crisis" Conference, 1989 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1992; (2 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 14-15)
    - Course Materials, 1981-1992
      - General, 1981-1992 (Box 50, Folder 16)
      - "Black Women Writers", 1989-1990 (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - Grades, 1985-1990 (RESTRICTED) (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - English Department Materials, 1988-1990 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Payroll Material, 1989-1990 (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Printed Material, 1981-1993; (2 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 22-23)
    - Tenure Controversy, 1982-1990
      - General, 1982-1990; (2 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 24-25)
      - "Apartheid at Rutgers: An Open Letter", 1990 (Box 50, Folder 26)
    - Tuition Hikes Activism, 1976 (Box 50, Folder 27)
  - State University of NewYork--Stony Brook, 1979-2002
    - General, 1985-2002 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - African American Studies Program, 1982-1994; (2 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 2-3)
    - Anti-Apartheid Activism, 1979-1985 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Conferences, 1993-1996 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Contract, 1983-1988 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and Memos, 1979-2002; (5 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 7-11)
    - Course Materials, 1980-1992
      - General, 1980-1992; (3 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 12-14)
      - AFS 300: "Blacks and the City", 1986; (2 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 15-16)
      - Directed Reading Lists, 1980 (Box 51, Folder 17)
      - Grades, 1981-1990 (Restricted) (Box 51, Folder 18)
      - Lectures and Outlines, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
      - Dube Tenure, 1980-1987; (2 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 2-3)
      - Health Insurance, 1979-1983 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - McAdoo Tenure, 1988-1990 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Printed Material, 1982-1995 (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - Retirement, 1994-1999 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - UNITI Cultural Center, 1988-1989 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Student Essays, 1988-2004 (Box 28)
  - Student Essays, 1988-2004; (2 Folders) (Box 89)
- Series IV: Activism, 1967-2006
  Baraka's political and cultural activism is the subject of this series, which includes organizational material, meeting minutes, writings, research reports, flyers and other printed material relating to his work with groups such as the Congress of Afrikan People, Black Radical Congress, Afrikan Free School, the Baraka Defense Committee, the Committee for a Unified Newark, Lincoln Park Coast Cultural District, and various Newark governmental and arts organizations including the public schools. It also contains campaign materials relating to the various political campaigns of Baraka's son, Ras. The materials are arranged alphabetically by organization name.
  - General, 1977-2006; (4 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 1-4)
  - Afrikan Free School, 1971-1976
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Grades, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Organizational Material, 1971-1975; (5 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 7-11)
    - Printed Material, 1972 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Reports, 1972-1976; (3 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 13-15)
  - Anti-Imperialist Cultural Union, 1976 (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Baraka Defense Committee, 1979 (Box 89)
  - Black Issues Convention, 1984 (Box 89)
  - Black Radical Congress, 1998-2000 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Black Radical Congress, 1998-2000; (4 Folders) (Box 89)
  - Congress of Afrikan People, 1971-1999
    - General, 1974-1976 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Organizational Materials, 1975-1999 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Research Material, 1970-1975 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Writings, 1971-1975 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Committee for Unified NewArk, undated (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - "Hatcher"--National Black Political Convention", 1997 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - League of Revolutionary Struggle Study Guide, undated (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Lincoln Park Coast Cultural District, 1989-2002
    - General, 1999-2002; (2 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 9-10)
    - Reports, 2000-2001
      - "Concept Development Plan", 2001 (Box 54, Folder 11)
      - "Master Plan", 2001 (Box 54, Folder 12)
      - "Recommended Strategy", 2000 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Writings and Meeting Notes, 1989-2000
      - General, 1989-2000; (3 Folders) (Box 54, Folder 14-16)
      - "Barbary Coast Renewal Project", 1989-1997 (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Newark City Government, 1984-2005
    - General, 1997-2005 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Reports,1984-2000
      - "A Plan to Restore the Krueger-Scott Mansion into the Newark Library and Museum of Black Culture", 1984 (Box 55, Folder 3)
      - "Proposed Newark Civic Center Complex", 1989 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - "Strengthening the Newark Arts Council", 2000 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Newark Collaboration Group, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Newark Cultural and Arts Activism, 1985-1986 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Newark Election, 1986 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Newark Music Project, 1989-2005
    - General, 1989-2005; (2 Folders) (Box 55, Folder 9-10)
    - Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Meeting Minutes and Writings, 1998-2003 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - "New Arkestra Repertory "Lost Jazz Shrines", 1998 (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Newark Public Schools, 1971-2006
    - General, 1971-1990; (8 Folders) (Box 55, Folder 14-21)
    - "An Action Plan for the Newark District", 1985 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - "Curriculum Guide Proposal United States History I", 1987 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - "Curriculum Guide Proposal United States History II", 1987 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - "Helping Educators Prepare their Students for the High School Proficiency Test", 1985 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - "An Improvement Plan for the Newark District", 1985 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - "Multiethnic/Multicultural Education Materials: An Annotated Listing", 1989 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - "Recommended New Listings to Textbook Catalog", 1990 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - "Secondary English", 1988 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - "Setting the Record Straight", 1973-1986 (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - "Snapshot of Our Schools,", 2000; (3 Folders) (Box 56, Folder 10-12)
  - Newark Rebellion, 1967 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - "Newark's A Moverin'", 1973 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - New Jersey Performing Arts Center, undated (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - People's Coalition Against the Budget Cuts, 1971-1976; (3 Folders) (Box 56, Folder 16-18)
  - Proposal for Merger with LRS, undated (Box 89)
  - Proposal for the South Park Church Performance Space", 1999 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Ras Baraka Political Campaigns, 1994-2006
    - Correspondence, 1998-2006 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Organizational Material, 1998-2006 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Printed Material, 1994-2006 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Voter Registration Information, 2002; (2 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 12-13)
    - Writings, 1994-2005 (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Rent Strike, 1974 (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - Shani Project, 2003 (Box 56, Folder 21)
  - Soyikwa Institute of African Theatre, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 22)
  - Wequahic Park Association, 1992 (Box 56, Folder 23)
  - Writings, 1979-2006 (Box 56, Folder 24)
- Series V: Kimako's Blues People, 1987-2004
  This series contains materials relating to Kimako's Blues People, a small club, music and performance venue, arts space, and salon operated out of Baraka's basement in Newark, NJ. Included are writings about KBP, correspondence, organizational materials, photographs, and flyers and clippings of shows and events at KBP. The series is arranged according to type of material.
  - AIR Program, 1993 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1987-2004 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Organizational Material, 1987-2001; (3 Folders) (Box 57, Folder 3-5)
  - Photos, 1988 (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Printed Material, 1987-2000
    - Clippings, 1987-1997 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Flyers, 1987-2000; (3 Folders) (Box 57, Folder 8-10)
  - Redemption Song Conference, 1989 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Writings, 1987-2002; (2 Folders) (Box 57, Folder 12-13)
- Series VI: Personal, 1956-2014
  This series contains material relating to Baraka's personal life. The bulk of this series consists of Baraka's handwritten notebooks, notes, planners, and calendars. Another major grouping pertains to Baraka's family. The rest of the series contains financial, legal, medical, and royalty documents, photographs and printed material relating to major events in Baraka's life, and Freedom of Information Act-acquired FBI files on Baraka. Finally, subject files relating to Baraka's research and writing interests are contained herein.
  - 60th Birthday, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - "Amiri Baraka Papers" Notes, undated; (2 Folders) (Box 66, Folder 7-8)
  - Amiri Baraka Funeral Program, 2014 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Awards, 1992-1999 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - "B&B: Baraka Book & Birthday Bash,", 2009
    - "NPL Mtg. Room Application Proposal, Proposal Notes", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - "Notes from Weekly Meeting Amiri B 75 Planning Committee", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - "Emails Back & Forth", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - "Flyers & Invitations", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - "Food, Bakery, Balloons, Flowers for Amina, the Poets", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - "Amiri B 75 Souvenir Journal AD Forms", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - "Anthology", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - "Baraka's Plays (Videos) @ NPL_Other Copy of Unity & Struggle", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - "Something in the Way of Things Bryan Green DVD", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - "Articles from Newspapers, Magazines, Celeste Bateman P.R.", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - "Booksellers", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - "Baraka Bibliography & Criticism", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - "Celeste Bateman's PowerPoint Presentation", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - "Article in Frost Illustrated", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - "Photographs of /010/8, '09", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - "DVD of B & B: Baraka Book & B'day Bash, NPL, 10/8/09", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - "Printed Program, Souvenir Journal", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - "Evaluation Form", 2009 (Box 68, Folder 18)
  - Birthday, 1970 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Bowling Scrapbook, 1957 (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - CVs, 1963-2003 (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Family, 1966-2005
    - General, undated (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Archie Family Reunion, 1989 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Baraka, 1983-2005
      - Ahi, 1986-2005
        - General, 1986-2005 (Box 65, Folder 6)
        - Grades, 1991 (RESTRICTED) (Box 65, Folder 7)
      - Amiri, Jr. Howard University Grades, 1990-1992 (RESTRICTED) (Box 65, Folder 8)
      - Kimako, 1985-1987 (Box 65, Folder 9)
      - Obalaji, 1983-2003
        - General, 1983-2003 (Box 65, Folder 10)
        - Grades, 1986-1988 (RESTRICTED) (Box 65, Folder 11)
      - Ras, 1986-1990
        - General, 1988-1990 (Box 65, Folder 12)
        - Grades, 1986-1988 (RESTRICTED) (Box 65, Folder 13)
      - Shani, 2003-2005 (Box 65, Folder 14)
    - Jones, 1966-1995
      - Anna Lois, 1987 (Box 65, Folder 15)
      - Coyt, 1966-1995 (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - Fidel Castro Harlem Visit Invitation, undated (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Financial
    - General, 1985-2004; (6 Folders) (Box 65, Folder 17-22)
    - Royalty Statements, 1981-2006 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - FOIA FBI Files, 1956-1980; (3 Folders) (Box 66, Folder 15-17)
  - House Mortgage, 1970 (Box 66, Folder 18)
  - Kwame Ture Memorial, 1999 (Box 66, Folder 19)
  - Legal, 1978-2005
    - General, 1978-2005; (2 Folders) (Box 66, Folder 2-3)
    - Contracts, 1984-2003; (2 Folders) (Box 66, Folder 4-5)
  - Lists, 1974 (Box 66, Folder 20)
  - Medical, 1993-2000 (Box 66, Folder 21)
  - Newark Arrest, 1968-1979 (Box 66, Folder 22)
  - Notes and Notebooks, 1968-2006
    - Notes, 1981-2007; (10 Folders) (Box 60, Folder 1-10)
    - Notebooks, 1968-2006; (2 Folders) (Box 60, Folder 11-12)
    - Notebooks, 1968-2006; (13 Folders) (Box 61, Folder 1-13)
    - Notebooks, 1968-2006; (13 Folders) (Box 62, Folder 1-13)
    - Notebooks, 1968-2006; (13 Folders) (Box 63, Folder 1-13)
    - Notebooks, 1968-2006; (7 Folders) (Box 64, Folder 1-7)
    - Notes, 1981-2007; (4 Folders) (Box 64, Folder 8-11)
    - Calendars, 2001-2006 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Address Books, undated; (3 Folders) (Box 65, Folder 1-3)
  - Passport, 1987-1997 (Box 66, Folder 23)
  - Phone Messages, (1991) (Box 66, Folder 24)
  - "Projects Outline", 1985 (Box 66, Folder 25)
  - Sheet Music, undated (Box 66, Folder 26)
  - Software--Floppy Disks and CD-ROMs, 1999-2006 (Box 66, Folder 27)
  - Sonia Sanchez Father Funeral, 2000 (Box 66, Folder 28)
  - Subject Files, 1977-2007
    - Actors, undated (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Actor's Theatre Workshop, 1985 (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - "Afro-American Novels Before 1980" List, undated (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - Brooklyn Center, 1998 (Box 57, Folder 18)
    - Brussels International Seminar, 1997 (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - Coltrane, John, 1984 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Communist Parties Meeting in Belgium, 1993 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Conferences, 1983-2003 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Dizzy Gillespie Funeral, 1993 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - "Film Festival Suggestions,", undated (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Fox, Donal, 1993-1995 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Harper, Billy, 2007; (2 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 7-8)
    - Jazz, 1995-2006; (2 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 9-10)
    - Jones, Quincy, 1990 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Malcolm X, 1990-2003; (2 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 12-13)
    - MLK Memorial, 1998-2004 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - National Black Arts Festival, 2004 (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - National Black Theatre Festival, 1989-1995 (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - New Jersey Budget Information, 1992 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - New Jersey v Peoples, 2004 (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Pan Africanist Congress, 1992-1993 (Box 59, Folder 19)
    - Roach, Max, 1991 (Box 59, Folder 20)
    - Sheet Music, undated (Box 59, Folder 21)
    - Simone, Nina, 1977-2003 (Box 59, Folder 22)
    - "Thelonious Monk Funeral,", 1982 (Box 59, Folder 23)
    - Thompson, Bob, 1966-1988 (Box 59, Folder 24)
    - Richard Wright, undated (Box 59, Folder 25)
  - Windows 95 Aptiva Startup Disk, undated (Box 66, Folder 30)
    - Notebooks, 1996-2004; (4 Folders) (Box 69, Folder 1-4)
- Series VII: Visual Art and Photographs, 1950-2007
  This series includes visual art in a variety of mediums both made by Baraka and by others. The series is arranged by medium, with each medium grouping given its own particular arrangement. The photographs grouping has two arrangements, by date and alphabetical by subject. Included in the photographs are portraits of Baraka, as well as images of his family and personal acquaintances, readings and performances, and productions of his plays. The visual art grouping contains primarily art made by Baraka in several mediums, including paintings, ink and pencil sketches, and computer generated (MS Paint).
  - Photographs, 1950-2008
    - General, 1950-2005
      - 1950-1959 (Box 70, Folder 1)
      - 1960-1969, (2 Folders) (Box 70, Folder 2-3)
      - 1970-1971, (2 Folders) (Box 70, Folder 4-5)
      - 1980-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 70, Folder 6-7)
      - 1990-1999, (4 Folders) (Box 70, Folder 8-11)
      - 2000-2005, (4 Folders) (Box 70, Folder 12-15)
      - Undated, (3 Folders) (Box 70, Folder 16-18)
      - Undated (Box 72, Folder 1)
      - Undated, (6 Folders) (Box 71, Folder 1-6)
    - Air Force, 1955-1956 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - "AB Roast", undated (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Abayomi, undated (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Album, undated (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - American Academy of Arts and Letters Ceremony,", 2001 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Amiri Baraka 60th Birthday (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - "Amiri Baraka & Allen Ginsberg", 1994 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - "Amiri Baraka & May a Angelou at the Schomberg Center Dancing on Langston Hughes' Ashes,", undated (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - "Amiri Baraka with Miguel Algarin", undated (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - "Amiri Baraka & Sunny Murray at DC Space", 1989 (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - Berlin, 1994 (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Berlin Jazz Festival, 1999 (Box 71, Folder 18)
    - "Black Arts Atlanta" Conference, 1994 (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - "Bumpy Slides,", 1991 (Box 71, Folder 20)
    - CAP, undated (Box 71, Folder 21)
    - CFUN, undated (Box 71, Folder 22)
    - Coltrane, John, 1959-1962 (Box 71, Folder 23)
    - Community Hospital, 2005 (Box 71, Folder 24)
    - Cuba, undated (Box 71, Folder 25)
    - DNC, 1988 (Box 71, Folder 26)
    - Digging, 2008 (Box 71, Folder 27)
    - Finland, 2001 (Box 71, Folder 28)
    - Gertrude Kay, 1931 (Box 71, Folder 29)
    - Guelph Jazz Festival, 2004 (Box 71, Folder 30)
    - Grachan Moncur, 1987 (Box 71, Folder 31)
    - Harlem Book Fair, 2004 (Box 71, Folder 32)
    - Joe Lee Wilson, 2007 (Box 71, Folder 33)
    - Ken Gibson, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 34)
    - Kimako's Blues People, 1991 (Box 71, Folder 35)
    - LA/Oakland, Dominique", 2005 (Box 71, Folder 36)
    - Lampkin, Shayla, undated (Box 71, Folder 37)
    - La Villette Jazz Festival, 1996 (Box 71, Folder 38)
    - Lisbon, undated (Box 71, Folder 39)
    - Malcolm X, (1996) (Box 71, Folder 40)
    - Meeting Lillie, undated (Box 71, Folder 41)
    - Miles Davis, 1983 (Box 71, Folder 42)
    - Moncada 50th Anniversary, 2003 (Box 71, Folder 43)
    - National Black Touring Circuit, undated (Box 71, Folder 44)
    - Negatives, 2003 (Box 71, Folder 45)
    - New Arkestra, 1998 (Box 71, Folder 46)
    - Nina Simone and Duma Ndlovu, 1985 (Box 71, Folder 47)
    - Orono Conference, 2000 (Box 71, Folder 48)
    - Ossie Davis, 1983 (Box 71, Folder 49)
    - Photo Album, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 50)
    - Police Assault on Amiri Baraka, 1979 (Box 71, Folder 51)
    - Promotional, by others, undated (Box 71, Folder 52)
    - "Ras", undated (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Ras Baraka and Sista Souljah, 1990 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Ras Campaign, undated (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - "Ras Set 01", 2001 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - "Somebody Blew Up America" Rally, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Shani Funeral, 2003 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - "Slide Order", undated (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Sonia Sanchez, undated (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Spirit House, 1970 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - St. Louis, 2005 (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - "Tanzania", 1971 (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - What was the Relationship of the Lone Ranger to the Means of Production Rehearsals and Performances, undated (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - "William Carlos Williams & Son, Patterson", undated (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - William Patterson College, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Visual Art, 1979-2004
    - By Baraka, 1995-2004
      - General, 1995-2004; (5 Folders) (Box 74, Folder 1-5)
      - Shows, 2004 (Box 74, Folder 6)
      - Sketchbook, undated (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - By Others, 1979-2002
      - General, 1989-2002 (Box 74, Folder 7)
      - M. Wagner, 1979-2001 (Box 74, Folder 8)
      - Portraits of Amiri Baraka, 1991-2002 (Box 74, Folder 9)
- Series VIII: Audio/Visual, 1959-2007
  This series includes audio cassettes, film reel, DVD, CD, and other AV formats both made by Baraka and by others. The series is arranged by medium, with each medium grouping given its own particular arrangement. The A/V materials contain VHS, Beta, 16mm and 35mm film reel, and DVD. The 174 numbered video reels are helical scan open reel film. The bulk of these materials contain footage of Baraka's various political activities throughout the seventies, including his involvement with the Kawaida Towers, the African Women's Conference, Black Women's United Front, and the Congress of African Peoples. A/V materials are arranged in the order in which they were given by Baraka. Finally, the audio group consists primarily of materials not created by Baraka, and previously released. However, of particular interest is a 1994 recording of a Baraka poetry reading, and a number of copies of a vinyl recording of songs written by Baraka, performed by The Advanced Workers with the Anti-Imperialist Singers. The audio materials are arranged by medium.
  - Audio, 1973-2007
    - Audiocassettes, 1959-2003
      - 1998 Essence Empowerment Series, 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        General
        0026817799
      - 600-1109872 FBI, 1993; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026819902
      - African Axemen, 1994; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026819481
      - Afternoon in Harlem, undated; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818809
      - Al Hawks: Dis Be de Hawkman, undated; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818272
      - Alive within… The Album, 1997; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026819830
      - Amiri Baraka @ 3rd Vision, undated; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818302
      - Amiri Baraka 3rd Vision, undated; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818167
      - Amiri Baraka Tribute, 2000-04-05; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818191
      - Amiri Baraka Yakkety Jazz, 1999; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818108
      - Amiri Baraka/Malachi Thompson Wealthy Theatre, 1999-11-13; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818132
      - Amiri Baraka: Who Speaks English in America?, 1997-06-02; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818779
      - BAM, 1962; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818051
      - Baraka House Oct 26/27 After Hours, undated; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818710
      - Baraka in Denver, 1979; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818434
      - Baraka reading, 1959-60; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818426
      - Barrett Warner/Bruce Jacobs, 1994; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026819910
      - Billy Capozzi w/ Finally Balanced, 1993-02-19; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026819694
      - Black Dada Nihilismus, 1995-12-12; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818701
      - Black Pig Liberation Front, There Is No God But God, 1996; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026819406
      - Black Reconstruction and Dubois' Theory of History, undated; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026819600
      - Blind Tom, undated, 1 audiocassettes (Box 86)
        Commercial
      - Blue Ark - Black History, 1994; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026820005
      - Blue Ark, Vision Festival, undated; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026818817
      - Bob Singleton: Riding on a Cloud, undated; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026819732
      - Buckminster Fuller: The 50-Year Experiment, 1983; 1 audiocassettes (Box 90)
        0026819430